<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<anydataset>
  <row>
    <field name="LANGUAGE">en-us</field>
    <field name="TITLE">XMLNuke Kernel Errors Module</field>
    <field name="MESSAGE">The requested module "{0}" caused an error. See below for more information.</field>
    <field name="MESSAGESITE">The requested site "{0}" caused an error. See below for more information.</field>
    <field name="TEXT_MODULE">Module:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_SITE">Site:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_ORIGINAL">Original Error Message:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_RELATED">Related Error Message:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CODE">Error Code:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_TYPE">Error Type:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CLASS">Error Class:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_FILE">Error in file:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_LINE">line </field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_STACKTRACE">Stack Trace:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_SQL">SQL Query:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_AMBIENTVARIABLES">Ambient Variables:</field>
    <field name="MSG_ERROR_UNKNOW">Unknow error.</field>
    <field name="CONTACTADMIN">If this problem persist contact your XMLNuke Administrator.</field>
    <field name="GOBACK">Try Again</field>
    <field name="404">Module not found</field>
    <field name="850">EditListObject does not exist none.</field>
    <field name="851">Erro in param type, that must be "SOFT" or "OFF".</field>
    <field name="852">XML file header bad formated.</field>
    <field name="853">Parameter must in inherit IXmlnukeDocumentObject Class.</field>
    <field name="750">The requested XSL don't exists in data directories.</field>
    <field name="751">Occurrs an error during try to load XSL file. Verify the file permission, correct formatting it or exists it.</field>
    <field name="752">Occurrs an error during try to load XSL cache file. Verify the file or directory permission and checking encoding it.</field>
    <field name="800">Fail when trying to load LANG file. Verify the file or directory permission and checking encoding it.</field>
    <field name="753">Don't possible to find user. It's null. Verify your Login Module check it's correct.</field>
    <field name="754">XSL Document does't found any repository.</field>
    <field name="755">Fail when trying to transform Document. The XSL Document can contains erros or invalid characters. \n First Step: Reset your cache. \n Second step: Verify if XSL Docuemnt contains erros and encoding.</field>
    <field name="756">The object return from your module is not a PageXml Class.</field>
    <field name="403">403 Forbbiden Error. You don't have privilege to access this page.</field>
    <field name="402">402 Not Authenticated Error. You need to make login to access this page.</field>
    <field name="600">XML Document don't exists in repository.</field>
    <field name="601">Invalid BTree. Recreate Index.</field>
    <field name="700">The format your timestamp date is bad. Verify timestamp format.</field>
    <field name="801">Image type not suported by image tool.</field>
    <field name="802">Image fails when creating from source. Verify image type or exists it.</field>
    <field name="821">Upload field name not contains a file.</field>
    <field name="822">Empty upload file name.</field>
    <field name="823">File size is greater that avaliable size.</field>
    <field name="824">Error when trying move uploaded file. It can't exists.</field>
    <field name="100">Fail when trying to open file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="101">Fail when trying to close file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="102">Fail when trying to read file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="103">Fail when trying to open directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="104">Fail when trying to read directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="105">Fail when trying to close directory becouse it not exists. First create the directory.</field>
    <field name="106">Fail when trying to delete file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="107">Fail when trying to delete directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="108">Fail when trying to create directory. Verify the parent directory permission.</field>
    <field name="109">Fail when trying to write in file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="250">XML Document not exists.</field>
    <field name="251">XML file header bad formated.</field>
    <field name="252">Error when loading the XML string. It can to be bad formated.</field>
    <field name="253">Fail when importing XML SimpleXmlObject to DOMObject.</field>
    <field name="254">Fail when trying to open XML Document. Verify the XML Document file permission, enconding and formating document.</field>
    <field name="255">Object must be a DOMDocument.</field>
    <field name="256">Fail when trying to save XML Document. Verify the XML Document file permission.</field>
    <field name="257">Object must be a DOMElement.</field>
    <field name="258">Fail when trying to create DOMElement Object.</field>
    <field name="1000">File path to save not found.</field>
    <field name="1001">Database don't exists.</field>
    <field name="1045">Access denied in try connect database.</field>
    <field name="1054">Fail in your SQL: {0}</field>
    <field name="1062">Just exists a occur this information in database.</field>
    <field name="1064">Invalid SQL Query.</field>
  </row>
  <row>
    <field name="LANGUAGE">pt-br</field>
    <field name="TITLE">XMLNuke Kernel Módulo de erros</field>
    <field name="MESSAGE">O módulo solicitado "{0}" provocou um erro. Veja abaixo mais detalhes</field>
    <field name="MESSAGESITE">O site solicitado "{0}" provocou um erro. Veja abaixo mais detalhes</field>
    <field name="TEXT_MODULE">Módulo:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_SITE">Site:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_ORIGINAL">Mensagem de Erro Original:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_RELATED">Mensagem de Erro Relacionado:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CODE">Cógido do Erro:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_TYPE">Tipo do Erro:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CLASS">Classe do Erro:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_FILE">Erro no arquivo:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_LINE">linha </field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_STACKTRACE">Pilha de Erros:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_SQL">Consulta SQL:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_AMBIENTVARIABLES">Variáveis de Ambiente:</field>
    <field name="MSG_ERROR_UNKNOW">Erro desconhecido.</field>
    <field name="CONTACTADMIN">Se o problema persistir contate o seu administrador XMLNuke.</field>
    <field name="GOBACK">Tentar Novamente</field>
    <field name="404">Módulo não encontrado</field>
    <field name="850">Não foi passado nenhum EditListObject para o EditList.</field>
    <field name="851">Erro no valor do parametro para congifurar o quebra de linha. Os valores devem ser "SOFT" ou "OFF".</field>
    <field name="852">Cabeçalho do arquivo XML está mal formatado.</field>
    <field name="853">O parametro deve herdar ou implementar a classe IXmlnukeDocumentObject.</field>
    <field name="750">O XSL solicitado não existe nos repositórios.</field>
    <field name="751">Ocorreu um erro durante a tentativa de carregar o arquivo XSL. Verifique a permissão do arquivo, sua formatação ou se ele existe.</field>
    <field name="752">Ocorreu um erro durante a tentativa de carregar o arquivo XSL de cache. Verifique a permissão do arquivo ou diretório e cheque sua codificação.</field>
    <field name="800">Falha ao tentar carregar o arquivo de linguagens. Verifique a permissão do arquivo ou diretório e cheque sua codificação.</field>
    <field name="753">Referencia ao usuário não encontrada. Verifique se seu Módulo de Login está correto.</field>
    <field name="754">O Documento XSL não foi encontrado em nenhum repositório.</field>
    <field name="755">Falha ao tentar transformar o documento XML. O documento XSL pode conter erros ou caracteres inválidos. \n Primeiro passo: Apague o seu cache. \n Segundo passo: Verifique se seu documento XSL contém erros e sua codificação.</field>
    <field name="756">O retorno do método CreatePage em seu módulo deve ser do tipo PageXml.</field>
    <field name="403">403 Acesso negado. Você não tem previlégios para acessar esta página.</field>
    <field name="402">402 Não autenticado. Você precisa logar para acessar esta página.</field>
    <field name="600">O Document XML solicitado não existe no repositório.</field>
    <field name="601">BTree Inválida. Recrie o índice.</field>
    <field name="700">O formato da data é inválido. Verifique os padrões timestamp.</field>
    <field name="801">O tipo da imagem não é suportada pela ferramenta de tratamento de imagens.</field>
    <field name="802">Falha ao criar a imagem. Verifique se o tipo é suportado ou a imagem existe.</field>
    <field name="821">O arquivo de upload não foi enviado ao servidor.</field>
    <field name="822">O nome do arquivo de upload é vazio.</field>
    <field name="823">Tamanho do arquivo é maior que o disponível pelo servidor.</field>
    <field name="824">Erro ao tentar mover o arquivo de upload. Este pode não existir.</field>
    <field name="100">Falha ao tentar abrir o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo ou se ele existe.</field>
    <field name="101">Falha ao tentar fechar o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="102">Falha ao tentar ler o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="103">Falha ao tentar abrir o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório.</field>
    <field name="104">Falha ao tentar ler o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório</field>
    <field name="105">Falha ao tentar fechar o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório</field>
    <field name="106">Falha ao tentar excluir o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="107">Falha ao tentar excluir o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório superior.</field>
    <field name="108">Falha ao tentar criar o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório superior.</field>
    <field name="109">Falha ao tentar gravar no arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="250">O Documento XML não existe.</field>
    <field name="251">O cabeçalho do arquivo está mal formatdo.</field>
    <field name="252">Erro ao carregar a string XML. Pode está mal formatado ou conter caracters inválidos.</field>
    <field name="253">Falha ao importar o documento XML SimpleXmlObject para DOMDocument Object.</field>
    <field name="254">Falha ao tentar abrir o documento XML. Verifique a permissão do arquivo, a codificação e a formatação do documento.</field>
    <field name="255">O objeto deve ser um DOMDocument.</field>
    <field name="256">Falha ao tentar salvar o documento XML. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="257">O objeto deve ser um DOMElement.</field>
    <field name="258">Falha ao tentar criar o objeto DOMElement.</field>
    <field name="1000">Não é possível salvar os dados. O caminho do arquivo AnyDataSet não foi encontrado.</field>
    <field name="1001">O Banco de dados não existe. Você deve cria-lo primeiro.</field>
    <field name="1045">Acesso negado ao tentar conectar ao banco de dados.</field>
    <field name="1054">Erro ao executar o SQL: {0}.</field>
    <field name="1062">Já existe uma ocorrência desta informação no banco de dados.</field>
    <field name="1064">Consulta SQL inválida.</field>
  </row>
</anydataset>
