<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<anydataset>
  <row>
    <field name="LANGUAGE">en-us</field>
    <field name="TITLE">XMLNuke Kernel Errors Module</field>
    <field name="MESSAGE">The requested module "{0}" caused an error. See below for more information.</field>
    <field name="MESSAGESITE">The requested site "{0}" caused an error. See below for more information.</field>
    <field name="TEXT_MODULE">Module:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_SITE">Site:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_ORIGINAL">Original Error Message:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_RELATED">Related Error Message:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CODE">Error Code:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_TYPE">Error Type:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CLASS">Error Class:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_FILE">Error in file:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_LINE">line </field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_STACKTRACE">Stack Trace:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_SQL">SQL Query:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_AMBIENTVARIABLES">Ambient Variables:</field>
    <field name="MSG_ERROR_UNKNOW">Unknown error.</field>
    <field name="CONTACTADMIN">If this problem persists contact your XMLNuke Administrator.</field>
    <field name="GOBACK">Try Again</field>
    <field name="404">Module not found</field>
    <field name="850">EditListObject does not exist.</field>
    <field name="851">Error in param type. It must be "SOFT" or "OFF".</field>
    <field name="852">Bad format of XML file header.</field>
    <field name="853">Parameter must inherit IXmlnukeDocumentObject Class.</field>
    <field name="750">The requested XSL doesn't exist in data directories.</field>
    <field name="751">An error occurred while trying to load XSL file. Verify the file permission, format it correctly and check if it exists.</field>
    <field name="752">An error occurred while trying to load XSL cache file. Verify the file or directory permission and check its encoding.</field>
    <field name="800">Failed when trying to load LANG file. Verify the file or directory permission and check its encoding.</field>
    <field name="753">Not able to find user. It's null. Verify your Login Module and check if it's correct.</field>
    <field name="754">XSL document didn't find any repository.</field>
    <field name="755">Failed when trying to transform document. The XSL document contains errors or invalid characters.\n First Step: Reset your cache.\n Second step: Verify if XSL document contains errors and check its encoding.</field>
    <field name="756">The object returned from your module is not a PageXml Class.</field>
    <field name="403">403 Forbidden Error. You don't have privilege to access this page.</field>
    <field name="402">402 Not Authenticated Error. You need to login to access this page.</field>
    <field name="600">XML document doesn't exist in repository.</field>
    <field name="601">Invalid BTree. Recreate Index.</field>
    <field name="700">The format of your timestamp date is bad. Verify timestamp format.</field>
    <field name="801">Image type not supported by image tool.</field>
    <field name="802">Image fails when creating from source. Verify image type and check if it exists.</field>
    <field name="821">Upload field name doesn't contain a file.</field>
    <field name="822">Empty upload file name.</field>
    <field name="823">File size is greater that allowed size.</field>
    <field name="824">Error when trying move uploaded file. It doesn't exist.</field>
    <field name="100">Failed when trying to open file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="101">Failed when trying to close file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="102">Failed when trying to read file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="103">Failed when trying to open directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="104">Failed when trying to read directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="105">Failed when trying to close directory because it doesn't exist. First create the directory.</field>
    <field name="106">Failed when trying to delete file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="107">Failed when trying to delete directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="108">Failed when trying to create directory. Verify the parent directory permission.</field>
    <field name="109">Failed when trying to write in file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="250">XML document doesn't exist.</field>
    <field name="251">Bad format of XML file header.</field>
    <field name="252">Error when loading the XML string. Perhaps it's not well formatted.</field>
    <field name="253">Failed when importing XML SimpleXmlObject to DOMObject.</field>
    <field name="254">Failed when trying to open XML document. Verify the XML document file permission, its enconding and the format of the document.</field>
    <field name="255">Object must be a DOMDocument.</field>
    <field name="256">Failed when trying to save XML document. Verify the XML document file permission.</field>
    <field name="257">Object must be a DOMElement.</field>
    <field name="258">Failed when trying to create DOMElement Object.</field>
    <field name="1000">File path to save not found.</field>
    <field name="1001">Database doesn't exist.</field>
    <field name="1045">Access denied while trying to connect to database.</field>
    <field name="1054">Failure in your SQL: {0}</field>
    <field name="1062">This information already exists in the database.</field>
    <field name="1064">Invalid SQL Query.</field>
  </row>
  <row>
    <field name="LANGUAGE">pt-br</field>
    <field name="TITLE">XMLNuke Kernel Módulo de erros</field>
    <field name="MESSAGE">O módulo solicitado "{0}" provocou um erro. Veja abaixo mais detalhes</field>
    <field name="MESSAGESITE">O site solicitado "{0}" provocou um erro. Veja abaixo mais detalhes</field>
    <field name="TEXT_MODULE">Módulo:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_SITE">Site:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_ORIGINAL">Mensagem de Erro Original:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_RELATED">Mensagem de Erro Relacionado:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CODE">Cógido do Erro:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_TYPE">Tipo do Erro:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CLASS">Classe do Erro:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_FILE">Erro no arquivo:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_LINE">linha </field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_STACKTRACE">Pilha de Erros:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_SQL">Consulta SQL:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_AMBIENTVARIABLES">Variáveis de Ambiente:</field>
    <field name="MSG_ERROR_UNKNOW">Erro desconhecido.</field>
    <field name="CONTACTADMIN">Se o problema persistir contate o seu administrador XMLNuke.</field>
    <field name="GOBACK">Tentar Novamente</field>
    <field name="404">Módulo não encontrado</field>
    <field name="850">Não foi passado nenhum EditListObject para o EditList.</field>
    <field name="851">Erro no valor do parametro para congifurar o quebra de linha. Os valores devem ser "SOFT" ou "OFF".</field>
    <field name="852">Cabeçalho do arquivo XML está mal formatado.</field>
    <field name="853">O parametro deve herdar ou implementar a classe IXmlnukeDocumentObject.</field>
    <field name="750">O XSL solicitado não existe nos repositórios.</field>
    <field name="751">Ocorreu um erro durante a tentativa de carregar o arquivo XSL. Verifique a permissão do arquivo, sua formatação ou se ele existe.</field>
    <field name="752">Ocorreu um erro durante a tentativa de carregar o arquivo XSL de cache. Verifique a permissão do arquivo ou diretório e cheque sua codificação.</field>
    <field name="800">Falha ao tentar carregar o arquivo de linguagens. Verifique a permissão do arquivo ou diretório e cheque sua codificação.</field>
    <field name="753">Referencia ao usuário não encontrada. Verifique se seu Módulo de Login está correto.</field>
    <field name="754">O Documento XSL não foi encontrado em nenhum repositório.</field>
    <field name="755">Falha ao tentar transformar o documento XML. O documento XSL pode conter erros ou caracteres inválidos. \n Primeiro passo: Apague o seu cache. \n Segundo passo: Verifique se seu documento XSL contém erros e sua codificação.</field>
    <field name="756">O retorno do método CreatePage em seu módulo deve ser do tipo PageXml.</field>
    <field name="403">403 Acesso negado. Você não tem previlégios para acessar esta página.</field>
    <field name="402">402 Não autenticado. Você precisa logar para acessar esta página.</field>
    <field name="600">O Document XML solicitado não existe no repositório.</field>
    <field name="601">BTree Inválida. Recrie o índice.</field>
    <field name="700">O formato da data é inválido. Verifique os padrões timestamp.</field>
    <field name="801">O tipo da imagem não é suportada pela ferramenta de tratamento de imagens.</field>
    <field name="802">Falha ao criar a imagem. Verifique se o tipo é suportado ou a imagem existe.</field>
    <field name="821">O arquivo de upload não foi enviado ao servidor.</field>
    <field name="822">O nome do arquivo de upload é vazio.</field>
    <field name="823">Tamanho do arquivo é maior que o disponível pelo servidor.</field>
    <field name="824">Erro ao tentar mover o arquivo de upload. Este pode não existir.</field>
    <field name="100">Falha ao tentar abrir o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo ou se ele existe.</field>
    <field name="101">Falha ao tentar fechar o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="102">Falha ao tentar ler o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="103">Falha ao tentar abrir o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório.</field>
    <field name="104">Falha ao tentar ler o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório</field>
    <field name="105">Falha ao tentar fechar o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório</field>
    <field name="106">Falha ao tentar excluir o arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="107">Falha ao tentar excluir o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório superior.</field>
    <field name="108">Falha ao tentar criar o diretótio. Verifique a permissão do diretório superior.</field>
    <field name="109">Falha ao tentar gravar no arquivo. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="250">O Documento XML não existe.</field>
    <field name="251">O cabeçalho do arquivo está mal formatdo.</field>
    <field name="252">Erro ao carregar a string XML. Pode está mal formatado ou conter caracters inválidos.</field>
    <field name="253">Falha ao importar o documento XML SimpleXmlObject para DOMDocument Object.</field>
    <field name="254">Falha ao tentar abrir o documento XML. Verifique a permissão do arquivo, a codificação e a formatação do documento.</field>
    <field name="255">O objeto deve ser um DOMDocument.</field>
    <field name="256">Falha ao tentar salvar o documento XML. Verifique a permissão do arquivo.</field>
    <field name="257">O objeto deve ser um DOMElement.</field>
    <field name="258">Falha ao tentar criar o objeto DOMElement.</field>
    <field name="1000">Não é possível salvar os dados. O caminho do arquivo AnyDataSet não foi encontrado.</field>
    <field name="1001">O Banco de dados não existe. Você deve cria-lo primeiro.</field>
    <field name="1045">Acesso negado ao tentar conectar ao banco de dados.</field>
    <field name="1054">Erro ao executar o SQL: {0}.</field>
    <field name="1062">Já existe uma ocorrência desta informação no banco de dados.</field>
    <field name="1064">Consulta SQL inválida.</field>
  </row>
  <row>
    <field name="LANGUAGE">de-de</field>
    <field name="TITLE">XMLNuke Systemkern-Fehler-Modul</field>
    <field name="MESSAGE">Das angeforderte Modul "{0}" verursachte einen Fehler. Mehr Informationen dazu finden Sie unten.</field>
    <field name="MESSAGESITE">Die angeforderte Seite "{0}" verursachte einen Fehler. Mehr Informationen dazu finden Sie unten.</field>
    <field name="TEXT_MODULE">Modul:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_SITE">Seite:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_ORIGINAL">Original-Fehlermeldung:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_RELATED">Verwandte Fehlermeldung:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CODE">Fehler-Code:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_TYPE">Fehler-Typ:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_CLASS">Fehler-Klasse:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_FILE">Fehler in Datei:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_LINE">Zeile </field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_STACKTRACE">Stack-Trace:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_ERROR_SQL">SQL-Anfrage:</field>
    <field name="TEXT_AMBIENTVARIABLES">Umgebungs-Variablen:</field>
    <field name="MSG_ERROR_UNKNOW">Unbekannter Fehler.</field>
    <field name="CONTACTADMIN">Falls dieses Problem weiterhin besteht kontaktieren Sie Ihren XMLNuke-Administrator.</field>
    <field name="GOBACK">Erneut versuchen</field>
    <field name="404">Modul nicht gefunden</field>
    <field name="850">EditListObject existiert nicht.</field>
    <field name="851">Fehler in Parameter-Typ. Muss "SOFT" oder "OFF" sein.</field>
    <field name="852">Falsches Format des XML-Datei-Kopfes.</field>
    <field name="853">Parameter muss IXmlnukeDocumentObject-Klasse übernehmen/erben.</field>
    <field name="750">Die angeforderte XSL-Datei existiert nicht in den Daten-Verzeichnissen.</field>
    <field name="751">Ein Fehler trat beim Laden einer XSL-Datei auf. Überprüfen Sie die Zugriffsrechte auf die Datei, achten Sie auf ein korrektes Datei-Format und prüfen Sie ob die Datei existiert.</field>
    <field name="752">Ein Fehler trat beim Laden einer XSL-Cache-Datei auf. Überprüfen Sie die Zugriffsrechte auf die Datei oder das Verzeichnis und prüfen Sie die Kodierung.</field>
    <field name="800">Fehler beim Laden der Sprach-Datei. Überprüfen Sie die Zugriffsrechte auf die Datei oder das Verzeichnis und prüfen Sie die Kodierung.</field>
    <field name="753">Benutzer konnte nicht gefunden werden. Überprüfen Sie Ihr Login-Modul auf Korrektheit.</field>
    <field name="754">XSL-Dokument konnte keinen Speicherort finden.</field>
    <field name="755">Fehler beim Transformieren des Dokumentes. Das XSL-Dokument enthält Fehler oder ungültige Zeichen.\n Schritt 1: Setzen Sie Ihren Cache zurück.\n Schritt 2: Prüfen Sie ob das XSL-Dokument Fehler enthält und überprüfen Sie die Kodierung.</field>
    <field name="756">Das von Ihrem Modul zurückgegebene Objekt ist keine PageXml-Klasse.</field>
    <field name="403">403 Zugriff verweigert. Sie verfügen nicht über die erforderlichen Rechte um auf diese Seite zuzugreifen.</field>
    <field name="402">402 Nicht authentifiziert. Sie müssen sich anmelden um auf diese Seite zugreifen zu können.</field>
    <field name="600">XML-Dokument existiert nicht am Speicherort.</field>
    <field name="601">Ungültiger BTree. Index neu erstellen.</field>
    <field name="700">Falsches Format des Zeitstempels. Überprüfen Sie das Format.</field>
    <field name="801">Bild-Typ wird nicht vom Bild-Werkzeug untersützt.</field>
    <field name="802">Fehler beim Erstellen des Bildes. Überprüfen Sie den Bild-Typ und prüfen Sie ob die Datei existiert.</field>
    <field name="821">Upload field name doesn't contain a file.</field>
    <field name="822">Empty upload file name.</field>
    <field name="823">File size is greater that allowed size.</field>
    <field name="824">Error when trying move uploaded file. It doesn't exist.</field>
    <field name="100">Failed when trying to open file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="101">Failed when trying to close file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="102">Failed when trying to read file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="103">Failed when trying to open directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="104">Failed when trying to read directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="105">Failed when trying to close directory because it doesn't exist. First create the directory.</field>
    <field name="106">Failed when trying to delete file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="107">Failed when trying to delete directory. Verify the directory permission.</field>
    <field name="108">Failed when trying to create directory. Verify the parent directory permission.</field>
    <field name="109">Failed when trying to write in file. Verify the file permission.</field>
    <field name="250">XML-Dokument existiert nicht.</field>
    <field name="251">Bad format of XML file header.</field>
    <field name="252">Error when loading the XML string. Perhaps it's not well formatted.</field>
    <field name="253">Failed when importing XML SimpleXmlObject to DOMObject.</field>
    <field name="254">Failed when trying to open XML document. Verify the XML document file permission, its enconding and the format of the document.</field>
    <field name="255">Object must be a DOMDocument.</field>
    <field name="256">Failed when trying to save XML document. Verify the XML document file permission.</field>
    <field name="257">Object must be a DOMElement.</field>
    <field name="258">Failed when trying to create DOMElement Object.</field>
    <field name="1000">Speicher-Pfad nicht gefunden.</field>
    <field name="1001">Databank existiert nicht.</field>
    <field name="1045">Zugriff auf die Datenbank verweigert.</field>
    <field name="1054">SQL-Fehler: {0}</field>
    <field name="1062">Diese Information ist schon in der Datenbank vorhanden.</field>
    <field name="1064">Ungültige SQL-Anfrage.</field>
  </row>
</anydataset>
